# **REONA WISE**

# **Project Consultant**

Passionate & Effective Advocate For Causes That Fundamentally Change People's Lives

#### **Phone:**

618.791.5694

#### **Email:**

Mrs.ReonaWise@gmail.com

### **HIGHLIGHTS**

✓ Development and grants management:

Managed over \$10 million in grants for local initiatives that impact poor and disadvantaged populations. Raised over \$500 thousand in corporate grants for various programs. Developed comprehensive fundraising strategies for local organizations involving foundation grants, corporate contributions, and individual donor programs.

#### ✓ Proactive, visionary business leader:

known for ability to win fiercely loyal community support, develop key coalitions and build crucial relationships with a shared sense of purpose. Extensive experience in the development, growth, team building, and leadership of paid and volunteer personnel. Skilled provider of advanced training, guidance, and motivation that result in the retention of top performing professionals.

#### **✓ Budget management:**

Extensive background in developing and monitoring program and organizational budgets. Well-versed in assisting organizations with federal, state, and coportatore reporting.

# Advocacy work and constituency building:

Extensive experience in articulating issues in education and youth programming as they relate to economic and social development. Pioneered successful youth programs resulting in reduction of high school truancy.

# **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Over 15 year's executive management and consulting experience including non-profit, private business and state and local government.

Enterprising leader with an impressive history of building programs that community values, driving advocacy initiatives that work, developing messages that inspire, and delivering communications that breakthrough. Advanced skills in strategic planning, development and tactical execution of award-winning programs that fundamentally change and benefit children and youth's lives.

### **EXECUTIVE EXPERIENCE**

## LESSIE BATES DAVIS NEIGHBORHOOD HOUSE, East St. Louis, IL

Vice President of Education & Youth Programs

- Responsible for overseeing grant management including review of staff time, program invoices, and program performance measures for all Early Childhood and Youth Programming
- Provide assistance in writing, reviewing and submitting all educational and youth program grants
- Effectively developed and implemented a comprehensive referral process for families needing supportive services
- Create strategies for program recruitment and high visibility in the community.
- Development, Implementation, and Update of continuous program manuals
- Coordinate staff training, professional development and recognition
- Communicate the mission, goals, and outcomes of educational and youth program to stakeholders, donors, funders and to the broader community through presentations, print and online media.
- Develop a continuous quality improvement plan for all programs based on accreditation measures.
- Ensure contract objectives, performance measures, and activities are being met and maintain quality data and evaluation tools for all programing
- Participate in community/public relations activities and professional or program-related network for Out of school time Youth Programing and Early Childhood Education

### **Program Coordinator**

### Jun 2016-Sep 2016

Sep 2016-Present

- Engaged and built relationships with stakeholders in order to involve them in the All Our Kids (AOK) Network, a collaboration of cross-sector membership working to improve early childhood outcomes in Greater East St. Louis
- Convened and facilitated the AOK collaboration to improve access to early childhood developmental and social-emotional screenings, coordinate community-wide screenings, and improve the quality of early childhood services in the community
- Lead Network partners in the completion of a community assessment, utilizing primary and secondary data, to identify priority areas within the early childhood system, in order to create a strategic plan that targets these priority areas
- Hosted and coordinated monthly parent cafes that engage parents around a specific topic, while having meaningful conversations and building relationships amongst parents
- Linked families with community agencies and resources

#### INDEPENDENT CONSULTANT, St. Louis MO

Strategic Planning Consultant and Project Management

2010-Present

- Work with businesses and organizations to rapidly change developments and challenges that businesses will face in coming year
- Aiding management in pragmatic planning to create the financial, risk management and operational plans that will focus
- $\ensuremath{ \bullet}$  resources needed to execute the strategic plan
- One-on-One developmental coaching
- Analyze businesses practices and processes both internal and external and determine if there is a need or change necessary to reach goals of success.
- Create Strategic Plans and goals that are obtainable and measureable for the business and help them to implement the plan
- $\ \ \, \ \ \,$  Implement plans to businesses and organizations to have satiability and growth
- Efficiently synthesize project information and accurately establish project scope



# CORE COMPETENCIES

- ✓ Educational Services
- ✓ Program Development & Implementation
- ✓ Strategic Planning and Leadership
- ✓ Goal/Growth Attainment
- ✓ Project Planning/Execution
- ✓ Website Design
- ✓ Corporate Training
- ✓ Microsoft Office & Adobe
  Suite
- ✓ Performance Management
- ✓ Operational Processes/Standards
- ✓ Cross-Functional Team Leadership
- ✓ Financial/Budget Plan Development
- ✓ Internal & External Communication
- ✓ Critical Analysis & Problem Solving
- ✓ Decision Making
- ✓ Grant/Proposal Writing
- ✓ Organizational Skills
- ✓ Funding & Development
- ✓ Reporting/Analyzing
- ✓ Donation/Fundraising Database
- ✓ Community Collaboration

# AWARDS & ACOMPLISHMENTS

- ✓ Awarded Grace Hills Women's Business Center Hall of Fame
- ✓ Achieved NAYCE accreditation at Early Childhood Center
- ✓ Obtained Illinois' ExceleRate Gold Circle of Quality and Eckert's Gold rating for Early Childhood Center
- ✓ Chair member of the Board for Illinois Partners for Human Services
- ✓ Implementation of Efforts to Outcome management database system
- ✓ Awarded Community Hero for Education award through Harmony Healthcare

- Plan, direct, and coordinate activities of multiple projects ranging in value from \$25,000 - \$3,100,000
- Maintain communication with project stakeholders and manage expectations Strategic Business and Organization Partners:

Riverview Garden School District, Lessie Bates Davis Neighborhood House, St. Louis Community College, True Fellowship Church, Chips Health and Wellness Center, JPEK Creative Works, City of Chicago, City of Chicago Events & Festivals, Chicago Housing Authority, Skye Sports Academy Organization, Grace Hill Settlement House, Better Family Life

#### BETTER FAMILY LIFE, St. Louis MO

Career Advisor (Contractor)

2013

- Served as liaison between employer and clients to meet immediate needs of employer and help the client retain employment
- Collected required data on all clients and maintain accurate records in statewide database
- ❖ Completed applicant pre-screening for employer recruitment/hiring events
- Prepared monthly reports on client's outcomes and additional achievements and attend regular training, workshops, and staff meeting
- Assisted all clients with high customer service and abide by all necessary codes of conduct
- Created internal forms and external marketing materials
- \* Case Management for all active and inactive clients on case load

#### EDSI-CHICAGOSERVICEWORKS, Chicago IL

Program Manager (Contractor)

2012-2013

- ❖ Management of 300+ transitional job placement participants throughout the city of Chicago at over 80 worksites
- Successful execution of programs' contractual goals and outcomes
  - > 75 percent of job placement
  - 95 percent completion of Job Readiness and Customer Service Training
  - > 75 percent of participant job readiness improvement
- Development and implementation of On the Job Training courses, Interviewing Workshops, and Resume Writing
- Creation of Business to Business Relationships for job placement opportunities
- Coordination of program timelines, scheduling, human resourcing, policy and procedures, and various program process flows
- Assisted in Workforce Investment Act departmental programming, job recruiting and placement
- Case Management for all active and inactive participants

#### PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

LESSIE BATES MADISON/St. Clair County, IL

Project Manager (Youth Employment Program), (Independent Contractor)

2010-2011

CHIPS HEALTH & WELLNESS CENTER, St. Louis, MO,

Executive Administrative Manager

2008-2010

UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI- GEAR UP PROGRAM, St. Louis, MO,

Site Coordinator

2006-2008



## **EDUCATION**

Southern Illinois University,

Edwardsville, IL Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Southern Illinois University,

Edwardsville, IL Masters of Public Administration and Public Policy

Parentsas Teacher Certified Certified National Playground Inspector

# FUNDRAISING EVENTS

Back to School Jamboree 2007-2017

Gala & Silent Auction 2009-2014

JPEK Creative Works Real Life Production 2007-2014

Chicago Gospel Festival 1997-2012

Run/Walk & Community Health Fair 2008-2010

Annual Prayer Breakfast 2008-2010

Black Expo of St. Louis MO 2006-2010

Music in Madison 2008-2009

Queen Court (College Scholarships Fund) 1997-2002

### **GRANTS**

*	The ASC Foundation	2008		
*	AMA Foundation	2008		
*	Wal-Mart, 2009			
*	Susan G. Komen Breast Cancer	2009/2010		
*	Express Scripts, 2009 & 2010			
*	Missouri Foundation for Health – Building Capacity	2009 &2010		
*	Missouri Foundation for Health – Women's Health	2010		
*	Missouri Foundation for Health – Health Literacy	2009		
*	Daughters of Charity	2009		
*	Barnes Jewish Christian Foundation	2009/2010		
*	Regional Arts Commission	2009/2010		
*	MHB Foundation	2011		
*	Job Training & Economic Development Grant Program	2011		
*	Workforce Investment Act			
	(Cook County Illinois & St. Louis County)	2011-2014		
*	Chicago Housing Authority			
	(Subsided Training/Employment Program)	2011-2013		
*	Summer Youth Employment Program (Illinois & Missouri)	2013-2017		
*	Early Childhood Prevention Initiative Block Grant, <b>997,000</b>	2016 & 2017		
*	Preschool For All Block Grant	2016 &2017		
*	Preschool For All Expansion, <b>344,000</b>	2017		
*	Teen REACH, <b>428,000</b>	2016-2017		
*	All Our Kids Network	2016-2017		
**	United Way one Time Grant	2016-2017		
*	Healthy Families Illinois	2016		
*	Healthy Communities	2017		
•	reading communication			

<b>WORKSHOPS/TRAININGS</b>	<b>AUDIENCE</b>	YEAR
Community Leadership	/Community Leaders/	2014-2017
Business Basics & Entrepreneurship	/Small Business Owners/	2014-2017
Empowering Young Women	/Youth (12-16)/	2006-2008
Pathfinder Training	/Youth (12-16) & Teachers/	2006-2008
College Planning	/Staff & Teachers/	2006-2015
Career & Professional Development	/Staff/	2007-2017
Motivational Speaking	/Various/	2006-2016
Administration in the Church	/Staff & Pastors/	2007-2015
Employee Values to Organization /Staf	2009	
Strategic Planning	/Managers/	2009-2016
Internal Database & Software Training	2006-2010	
Branding & Marketing Your Organization	2010-2016	
Professionalism in the Workplace	/Young Adults (18-25)/	2010-2013
Communication & Diversity in the World	2010-2012	
Company Retreat: Organizational Core	2010	
Job Readiness & Work Ethics Training	/Youth (16-21) & Adults/	2012-2016